A TOWN WITHOUT SEASONS
（沒有季節的城市）
[Okabe] Katsuko, when's your birthday?
小克，你的生日是哪一天？
Wait. Let me guess.
等等，讓我猜看看
I bet it's July.
是7月吧？
EPISODE 7 GANMODOKI: PART 1 OF 2
（第7集，油豆腐 前篇）
Then, is it August?
那麼是8月？
Not September, right?
不是9月吧？
October?
10月？
It's October!
原來是10月啊！
Then, are you a Libra?
那你是天秤座嗎？
Scorpio?
天蠍座？
Oh, then your birthday's coming up soon.
是喔，原來是天蠍座，那快到啦
[Hansuke] No, it's not really coming up soon.
也不算吧
It's way off.
還有一段時間
[Okabe] I wonder what I should get.
要送什麼禮物好呢？
What would make her happy?
她收到什麼禮物會開心呢？
I doubt anything would make her happy.
我覺得不管送她什麼，她都不會高興
Hey, don't say that about her.
喂，不要那樣說她
She may not look it, but she has many emotions.
別看她面無表情，也是有喜怒哀樂的
When she's happy, her brow unfurrows.
她高興的時候，眉間的皺紋會消失
When she's mad, her nostrils flare a little.
生氣的時候，鼻孔會稍微張大
When she's sad, she slouches a little.
難過的時候會有點駝背
When she's surprised,
而驚訝的時候
she stumbles.
她會往前絆倒
Nobody can see those tiny changes.
那些變化也太小了，誰看得出來啦
I know! Clothes.
還是送衣服好了！
Clothes? You're gonna buy her clothes for her birthday?
衣服？你要送她衣服當禮物？
I can't imagine how that would work.
好難想像你會成功
I wonder what she'd look good in.
她適合什麼樣的衣服呢？
What's she usually wear anyway?
她平常都穿什麼樣的衣服？
I don't know. I don't look at her clothes.
不知道，我沒有在注意耶
How old is she anyway?
話說她幾歲啊？
I have no idea.
我也不知道
It took me three years just to find out her birthday.
我花了三年才問到她的生日耶
Have her aunt and uncle always taken care of her?
一直都是她的伯父跟伯母 在照顧她嗎？
That's not quite the right nuance for their relationship.
兩者間有細微差別存在啊，阿半
[Hatsutaro] "Nuance"?
“細微差別”？
You're amazing, Masuo. You know some really big words.
不愧是有讀完高中的人 會的單字就是比較難
[Hansuke] What do you mean?
那是什麼意思？
Originally, after The What,
她們家在遭遇納尼後
Katsuko and her mom lived together alone.
剩克子跟她媽兩個人相依為命
Yeah. She was a single mother.
對，她們家是單親家庭
[Man-to-Man's owner] Welcome.
歡迎光臨
But then one day,
結果有一天
her mom abandoned Katsuko and left the town.
她媽拋下女兒，離開城市
She married some rich CEO.
跑去跟某間公司的社長再婚了
Then her aunt moved in with her husband.
後來她的伯父跟伯母來到這裡 厚著臉皮住進她家
You mean she sublet it?
是把房子轉租給他們嗎？
The uncle, Kyota, was a middle school teacher,
她的伯父京太以前是國中老師
but he drank too much and got fired.
但是因為酒品太差被炒魷魚了
Their income comes just from Katsuko's work at home
他們的收入來自克子做家庭代工
and the money Katsuko's mom sends.
還有她媽媽寄來的錢
That's the "nuance."
這就是我剛才提到的“細微差別”
So, the "nuance" is that Katsuko is the one taking care of the aunt and uncle?
所以“細微差別”是指 克子在照顧伯父跟伯母是吧？
How dare you say such a thing!
你這臭小子講什麼鬼話？
Sorry.
抱歉
-This guy's drunk. -Huh?
-這傢伙喝醉了 -什麼？
[customer] We once bargained with her mom,
我們曾經跟她母親談判過
and said we'd send Katsuko to high school if she increased
那時候我們說會送克子去上高中
the money she sent every month.
條件是每個月多送些生活費過來
[Hansuke] Is that him?
就是他？
Then…
結果啊…
her mom, the CEO's wife showed up.
社長夫人還真的駕臨此地
She reeked of perfume.
而且全身上下散發著香水味
[resident 1] Whose car is that?
這是誰的車子？
[resident 1] That's quite a car.
好高級的轎車
[resident 1] What's she here for?
她來這裡有什麼事？
Katsuko, it's your mother.
克子，媽媽來了
Come out and say hello.
快來打招呼
Katsuko?
克子？
Is it really you?
你真的是克子嗎？
[resident 2] That fancy way of
她身上的大衣就只是披著而已
Dear me.
討厭啦
You look like a crushed ganmodoki.
你看起來就像被壓扁的油豆腐呢
[Kyota] I know that
我都知道
ever since that day, you people, behind Katsuko's back,
從那天以後，你們都在背地裡
you call her "Ganmodoki."
把克子稱作“油豆腐”
But the people here, they never criticized that woman.
而城市的居民卻沒有說那女人的壞話
The same people who mock Katsuko and call her "Ganmodoki"
就連那些嘲笑克子是“油豆腐”的人
don't feel any hostility toward that arrogant rich snob,
面對傲慢的社長夫人也沒有半分不滿
and view her with admiration and envy.
而是朝她投以崇拜與羨慕的眼神
Do you know why that is?
你覺得這是為什麼？
[Hatsutaro] We'll be going now.
那我們該走了
-I'll pay, Masuo. -Thanks.
-大哥，這攤我出錢 -謝啦
-Come again. -Excuse me.
-歡迎再來 -不好意思
You go ahead and sit down.
你先等一下
Sit down.
先坐下
-Huh? -Sit.
-什麼？ -坐就是了
Tomorrow, 7:00 a.m.
明天7點喔
-Okay. -Thanks.
-好 -謝謝
Thank you.
謝謝惠顧
Thanks for the food.
謝謝招待
Now, let's look at it psychologically.
接下來要談的是心理學的領域
Let's say that CEO's wife came here
我們假設社長夫人
handing out relief supplies,
一邊分送救援物資
and saying, "Hang in there,"
一邊說“請各位加油”
and shaking people's hands. What would you think?
然後嘗試要握住你的雙手 你會有什麼想法？
It would tick me off.
我會不爽
How come?
為什麼？
That kind of thing is hypocrisy.
因為很虛偽啊
People commit hypocrisy to affirm their status and feel superior.
她這麼做是為了確定自己的地位 獲得優越感
It even says so in the Bible.
《聖經》上也有提到
"When you give to the needy, don't let your left hand know
“你施捨的時候
what your right hand is doing."
不要讓左手知道右手所做的”
Right? Go on, drink.
懂吧？來，喝吧
Thanks.
謝謝
The reason they aren't hostile to that CEO's wife is
這裡的居民沒對社長夫人抱持反感
because she is just like the people who live here.
是因為他們認為她是同類
Just like them?
同類？
She's one of them, but she's a success story.
夫人是從他們之中誕生的成功者
They also just might have a bright future like she's got.
他們認為自己也有可能擁有 一樣光明的未來
That's why they don't criticize her.
所以才沒有譴責
What about Katsuko?
小克呢？
She's the same as them.
她當然也是其中的一人
That's why they mock her.
所以才會被看不起
You could even say that they despise her.
不，或許說是恨她比較正確
But why?
為什麼？
Katsuko's so virtuous and dedicated, so why are they like that to her?
丹羽先生，這是為什麼？ 她明明堅強又奮發向上
Shouting at Tanba-san won't help.
你逼問他也沒有辦法改變現況
That's so cruel.
這樣太過分了
Calling her a rotten ganmodoki is so cruel.
竟然說她像是“腐爛的油豆腐” 太惡毒了
Not "rotten." "Crushed."
不是“腐爛的”是“被壓扁的”
She's hard-working, gets up before everyone,
她努力工作，總是第一個起床
and even sweeps
就算沒有拜託她
in front of the neighbors' homes though nobody asks her to.
她也會把鄰居的門前一起掃乾淨
Yeah, she's plain…
她是不太起眼沒錯…
and unsocial…
而且個性不討喜…
But she's a nice girl who doesn't bother anyone.
可是她不會給任何人添麻煩 是個好人啊
That's exactly the point.
你說到重點了
What's the point?
什麼重點？
We work and work, but are never rewarded,
我們日復一日工作卻沒有得到回報
and life never gets easier.
生活也沒有變得比較輕鬆
Katsuko is the embodiment of our unfair lot in life.
克子的人生就是 這不合理境遇的真實寫照
She's personified poverty.
如同現實版窮人
That's why she's hated.
所以他們才會恨她
Accepting her would mean accepting our own poverty.
畢竟接納她等於承認自己的貧乏
This is far enough.
送我到這裡就可以了
[Hansuke] Her aunt Taeko was to be hospitalized for three weeks.
克子的伯母妙子必須住院三個星期
Bye.
我走了
Don't push yourself too hard.
你別太勉強自己
Non-woven masks, huh?
不織布口罩？
Can't believe it has to be done by hand.
真沒想到這是手工做出來的
If only you were…
要是你…
a little more attractive…
長得美一點
and had a more feminine body…
身材好一點
If you were more like a womanly woman…
是個充滿女人味的正點女人…
…there are ways you could make money more easily.
就會有更輕鬆的方法賺錢了
But the way you are…
不過憑現在的你…
folding masks into bellows is the best you can do.
把口罩折成風琴摺就是極限了吧
The little mask girl.
我看你就是折口罩的少女
Pretty funny, huh?
好笑吧？怎麼樣？
[radio] "…so our opinions never matched."
意見完全相左
-[doorbell rings] -That's for sure.
這一點是確實的
"We often went to different…"
我們在同一期間在不同處…
[Okabe] Liquor Shop Okabe.
我是岡部酒鋪的員工
"…at the same time." I bet.
經常有那種事對吧？
"Eventually, we were able to take a vacation together.
不過我們曾經一起去旅行
It was when it wasn't hot or cold, during the change in seasons."
那是在季節轉變的時期 天氣不冷也不熱
I see. So that's what you wear.
我懂了，原來是這種感覺
Let's see. Hold on.
我明白了，你先別動
Don't cover up. Just one more. Don't worry. It's nothing.
不要遮，再拍一張就好 沒事的，不會怎樣
[Kyota] That's a real meteorological problem.
這是氣象的問題啊
Is he drunk again?
他又喝醉了嗎？
He's a good customer, so I hate to say it.
他是常客，所以我不太想這樣講
But he's a jerk for making you do all the work.
可是他真的是人渣 竟然讓你一個人工作
[Kyota] Katsuko!
克子！
Here, have this. Take it.
這個送你，拿著
I sent another letter
對了
to that radio program where they read listeners' letters. It's really good.
我又寫信寄去廣播電台了 這次可是我的自信之作
[Kyota] Katsuko!
克子！
I just know they'll read it this time, maybe.
他們這次一定會唸我寫的 應該會唸啦
[Hansuke] The next day,
到了隔天
we joined Okabe as he went shopping.
岡部找我們一起去買東西
Morning.
早啊
Hi.
嗨
-It's sunny. -It feels nice.
-是大晴天呢 -感覺很不錯
[Hansuke] Since the incident
在經歷流浪漢事件之後
with the homeless, it's been awkward around Tatsuya.
-我跟辰也之間的氣氛有點尷尬 -紅色會不會太高調？
Would it be like saying "stop"?
感覺像在叫對方站住？
There's no time to worry about that! We've gotta…
現在不是說那種話的時候 放著不管的話…
[Hansuke] I wonder if Tatsuya knows that I'm reporting on the town
辰也是不是已經發現 我會回報城市的狀況
and getting money to do it.
藉此收錢？
[Tatsuya] And white looks kinda like tofu…
而且白色又有點像豆腐…
Hansuke, you know this area?
阿半，這一帶你熟嗎？
Kinda.
算熟吧
I'd like to make a suit.
我想要請人製作一套西裝
Not at a clothing store, but at a proper place.
不是成衣量販店的那種 而是去好一點的店買
Tailor-made, huh?
量身訂製的那種？
Shima-san's actually pretty conservative.
島先生其實很保守
He wants full-time employees to wear a suit.
他希望正職員工都能穿西裝上班
Full-time employee…
正職員工…
[Hansuke] Tatsuya's boss has
辰也的上司
a connection with the guy who hired me.
和我的雇主也有關係
But I'm not exactly sure
但是那件事
what that means.
究竟代表什麼？
I've got it!
我知道了！
What's that all about?
幹嘛突然這麼大聲？
Something's seemed kinda off for a while.
我從剛才就覺得好像哪裡怪怪的
Like we don't fit in.
只有我們格格不入
Probably Hansuke's shorts.
是因為阿半穿短褲的關係吧？
Your sunglasses are pretty weird too.
你的墨鏡也沒好到哪裡去
It's because we're not wearing masks.
是因為我們沒戴口罩啦
I hate to repeat it, but those shorts are weird.
我是不想說第二次 不過怪的是你的短褲吧
Want to buy some?
要去買嗎？
I brought some.
我有帶
There you go.
來
[radio] "Then, after the meeting, the person who I'd never met before,
“然後那場會議結束之後
I was able to see them without their mask on.
我碰巧看到首次見面的人 拿下口罩的樣子
And you know what?
結果啊
Their face was exactly what I'd imagined…"
那個人的長相 跟我想像得一模一樣…”
[Kyota] This mackerel sure isn't very fresh.
這鯖魚真不新鮮
From a food preparation perspective…
這從食品烹調學…
No, wait.
不
From a food hygiene perspective…
從食品衛生學的角度來看…
[radio] "You're exactly what I thought…"
“我真心認為長得 跟我想像得完全一樣”…
[Kyota] Katsuko.
克子
[radio] "I thought they might not understand,
“不過我覺得對方可能無法明白 而且說這種話有些失禮
So, that's what happened."
這就是事情的經過”
I'd like my last name embroidered on the inside. Yoda.
請在內側加上姓氏的刺繡，我姓與田
Certainly.
好的
Right here.
加在這邊
-Around here. -Okay.
-大概這邊 -好的
[radio] This letter is from Un-jelled Pudding.
這封信來自不會凝固的布丁
Thank you for your letter.
謝謝你總是會寄信過來
I'd like to go to this listener's local supermarket.
我真想去布丁附近的超市逛逛
I'd like to meet this lady who offers samples to shoppers.
有那種試吃阿姨的話 大家都會想去看看吧，不過…
You can't tell unless someone wears it.
要有人穿才知道看起來是什麼感覺嘛
Me wearing it won't help.
叫我試穿有用嗎？
It's kind of odd.
我也不知道
You actually resemble Shinobu Otake.
感覺有點像大竹忍
[clerk] That's very cute, isn't it?
那一件很可愛吧？
I'm wearing the same dress.
跟我身上這件是一樣的喔
Shinsuke?
阿新？
It is you.
我沒認錯人吧？
-Hello. -[clerk] Hello.
-你好
Why are you here?
為什麼你會在這裡？
My friend's looking for a present for a girl.
我朋友來挑要送給女生的禮物
He shouldn't be asking you for help.
那也不能叫你試穿吧
This is what she's like.
那個女生長這個樣子
-She's cute. -[Okabe] Yeah, she sure is!
-好可愛 -對吧？
-She sure is. -Who's that?
-我也覺得她很可愛 -這個人是誰？
What would look good on her?
你覺得她適合什麼風格？
Well, let me think.
我想想看喔
This color would be better.
我覺得這個顏色比較適合她
Then I'll take it.
那我要這件
[radio] The listener's name is Second Drink is Otsutaro.
這位聽眾的暱稱是第二杯乙太郎
"I always enjoy listening to your show, Kotaro.
“小太郎先生的廣播節目 我每次都聽得很開心
I work at a convenience store.
我平常在便利商店打工
It's actually a liquor store…"
不過我原本是在酒鋪…”
It's no big deal.
這不是什麼大事
It's only natural.
這很正常
You just hold still.
你只要乖乖待著就好
[radio] "…there are no seasons."
“那裡沒有季節”
Close your eyes for this kind of thing.
這種時候你應該要閉上眼睛
Close them!
給我閉上！
Fine. I'll close my eyes.
可惡，算了，我閉眼
"…and a boat banner flaps in the wind.
“大漁旗隨風飛舞
There are lots of interesting adults and energetic children.
有許多有趣的大人 以及活力十足的孩子
One of them who I really like…"
其中我最喜歡的…”
Welcome home!
歡迎回來！
I'm back!
我回來啦！
-You're so late. -Welcome home.
-你好慢喔 -歡迎回來
Barbecue beef dinners.
來，這是燒肉便當
[Tatsuya's sister] It's from Jojoen!
是敘敘苑的耶！
I've also got pudding from Modando.
還有摩登堂的布丁喔
-What for? You got good news? -Just hurry and wash up.
-為什麼？發生什麼好事了嗎？ -別問了，快去洗手吧
[Tatsuya's brother] Okay.
好
[Tatsuya's brother] Akane, hurry up.
姊姊，你快一點啦
[Mrs. Yoda] Akane, do your homework later.
小茜，功課晚點再寫吧
Did you get good news?
有什麼好事嗎？
No, nothing.
沒有啊
I bet you did.
你才是，遇到好事了吧？
What?
什麼？
No, nothing at all.
沒有啦，怎麼可能
Really? But you look so happy.
真的嗎？不過你看起來很高興呢
Well, I get paid better than I ever have before.
現在跟之前比起來，薪水好很多
And my work is interesting.
工作內容也很有意思
But I'm mostly a gofer.
不過目前處理的全是雜事
It'll only get better.
我會越來越好的
Keep it up.
加油啊
I will.
好
I visited the hospital today.
我今天有去醫院
How's Shingo?
哥哥狀況如何？
He'll be discharged soon.
他好像可以出院了
But he's in a wheelchair.
只是得用輪椅
He may be in a wheelchair forever.
可能一輩子都得坐輪椅
I'm not sure what to do.
我也不知道該怎麼辦
We sure can't live here.
大概沒辦法住在這裡吧
It's too small and there are stairs.
這裡又小又窄，還有高低差的問題
Don't make that face.
別擺出那種表情嘛
Huh? What do you mean?
什麼？你是指什麼啊？
What face?
怎樣的表情？
I don't know what face I'm making.
我不知道自己露出什麼表情
The one that says, "Not again."
你的臉上寫著“又來了”
As if you're the lead character in a tragedy.
感覺把自己當成了悲劇主角
Shingo's the lead, right?
主角是哥哥吧？
To you, he's the tragic figure, not me.
對你來說，主角不是我 是他才對吧？
Okay, that's enough of this.
好了，別談這件事了
Go get a bath.
你去洗澡吧
I've got good news too.
我也有遇到好事啊
I went to get a suit made today.
我今天去訂製西裝了
One for work.
是穿去公司的西裝
You probably don't remember, Mom, but Akio, your father,
媽媽大概不記得吧？ 昭雄先生，也就是你們兩個的爸爸
had a suit made for me.
幫我做了西裝
I never got to wear it though.
但我沒有機會穿，一次也沒有
Hold on! That's my suit.
等等！這是我的西裝
And that's the money for my college. Give that back!
還有我上大學的學費，你不能拿走！
Got a problem with it?
有意見嗎？
[Tatsuya] So this time, I'm making one with the money I made.
所以我決定這次要用 我自己賺來的錢買西裝
A nice one, tailor-made.
買一套帥氣的訂製西裝
I ordered it, bought you presents, then came home,
我訂完西裝，帶著禮物回來
and you talk about Shingo.
然後你一開口就跟我提哥哥的事情
So, you're absolutely right about my look of, "Not again."
所以你說對了，超級正確 我剛才的表情就是“又來了”
What's wrong with talking about him?
我只是說一下，有什麼關係？
Am I not even allowed to talk about Shingo?
難道連稍微提到慎吾都不行嗎？
That's not what I mean.
我不是那個意思
Other things come first.
但是應該要有先後順序吧
First, we need to get on our feet again.
我們要先重建自己的生活
Then move to a bigger place. Then Shingo can join us.
搬去大一點的地方 再來考慮哥哥的事情
If we don't,
要不然…
it'll just happen again.
就只會重蹈覆轍啊
You're…
我說你啊…
so mean.
真不體貼
I know that!
我知道啊！
But you see…
我…
It's not that I hate Shingo.
我不是討厭哥哥
What I hate is how you get so blinded when it comes to Shingo.
我討厭的是只要一想到他 就會不顧周遭的你
When that happens…
就是因為那樣…
I hate how I become.
我討厭自己老是這樣
Dang it!
該死！
This house is so dang small!
這個家有夠小！
It's freakin' small!
小到氣死人！
There's nowhere to cool my head after arguing with my mom!
跟媽媽吵架之後 連個能冷靜的地方都沒有，可惡！
Tatsuya…
哥哥…
[Hansuke] Three weeks later, Katsuko's aunt got out of the hospital.
三個星期後，克子的伯母出院了
USE WATER FROM THE OUTDOOR FAUCET
（使用室外水龍頭的水）
[resident 5] Yeah, it's really delicious.
對呀，真的很美味呢
-Hello there. -There you are.
-嗨 -你好啊
[Hansuke] Katsuko became even busier.
克子變得更加忙碌
Her aunt was ordered to stay in bed for another month.
她的伯母被要求多靜養一個月
So Katsuko had to make hospital food for her every day.
克子因此必須每天做醫院餐
I'm so sorry.
不好意思啊
I intended to come straight back to work.
雖然我想要盡快開始工作
But the doctor…
可是醫生說…
Overdoing it is the worst you can do.
勉強自己最傷身體
Both medically and for efficiency.
不管是從醫學角度 還是效率方面來看都是如此
Katsuko, you'd better hurry.
克子，動作快一點
You need to pick up her medicine by 5:00 p.m.
你在5點之前要去拿她的藥
Right?
對吧？
It's been years since I was able to relax this much.
我都不知道自己有幾年沒這麼悠閒了
Is that what I think it is?
不會是那個吧？
It's done!
終於做好啦！
The tailor-made suit. Show me.
量身訂製的西裝，給我看看
-No way! No way! -[Hansuke] Just let me see.
-等等！不行！ -有什麼關係？看一眼就好了
I've gotta show it to my mom.
我要拿回去給我媽看
Hey, mister full-timer. Let's drink!
好，正職的，來喝吧！
-Congrats. -Thanks.
-恭喜啦 -謝謝
-Cheers! -Cheers! Cheers!
-乾杯！ -乾啦！
Oh no, Hatsu. This says "Strong."
糟糕，阿初，上面寫“超強”
Bring it on!
很好啊！
We'll see just who's stronger, dang it!
就來比看看我跟“最強”誰更厲害！
Have you even paid? I bet you haven't.
話說你付錢了嗎？還沒吧？
We'll pay after we drink, dang it.
喝完就會付啦，蠢蛋
Pay before you drink, dang it.
喝之前先付啦，笨蛋
Maybe I'll buy some champagne today.
今天買支香檳好了
It sure is unusual for you to come to the shop, Katsuko.
真是稀客，小克怎麼會來店裡？
What's up?
怎麼了？
Running an errand?
你來幫家人買東西嗎？
I heard your aunt was discharged.
我聽說你的伯母出院了
That's great. Have you put on some weight?
太好了，你是不是稍微變胖了一點？
Sorry! That was rude, wasn't it?
抱歉！我這樣算是在性騷擾？
Gee, I'm sorry.
天啊，我不是那個意思
The other day I went to a department store.
對了，我之前去百貨公司
Everyone in the city was wearing masks.
都市的人都戴著口罩呢
Everybody was wearing the masks you fold, Katsuko.
大家都戴著小克親手折出來的口罩耶
When I saw that, it made me happy.
我看到的時候，心裡莫名地高興
Is she okay?
她還好嗎？
I mean, she's slouching more than usual.
總覺得她的背比平常還要駝
Really?
什麼？
-You think so? -Yeah.
-有嗎？ -有啊
I'm home.
我回來了
I'M SORRY.
（對不起）
[Mrs. Yoda] Ryu.
小隆
Turn around and face me.
你轉過來一下
I've gotta fix this.
我弄一下
[Mrs. Yoda] Okay, let's go.
好，準備走囉
Unbelievable! How come I didn't notice sooner?
太誇張了！怎麼沒有早點發現？
No point in hiding it.
這種事隱瞞也沒有用
Who was it, Katsuko?
克子，對方是誰？
Who was it?
到底是誰？
[Hansuke] Katsuko
克子…
was pregnant.
懷孕了
[Okabe] Liquor Shop Okabe.
我是岡部酒鋪的員工
I've got a delivery.
我來送貨
[resident 6] Did you hear? A young lady's been visiting Hansuke.
你們知道嗎？聽說有年輕女生 經常住在三號棟的半助那裡
[resident 7] Naughty boy! But that's not all. Katsuko's gonna have a kid.
真是不檢點！不只如此 聽說二號棟的克子好像懷孕了
[resident 6] That crushed Ganmodoki? Naughty girl!
那個被壓扁的油豆腐？真不自愛！
[resident 7] And that goofy liquor shop kid's started playing guitar.
而且酒鋪老闆的那個傻兒子 開始彈起吉他了
-No way! -[resident 6] This town's going nuts.
-傷風敗俗！ -這城市到底出了什麼問題啊？
What's the world coming to?
這社會沒救啦
Translated by Brian Athey
字幕翻譯：陳亭萱